{"Topic": "Flower and its Parts", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which of the following protects the unopened flower?", "op1": "Petal", "op2": "Stamen", "op3": "Anther", "op4": "Sepal", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Anther is a part of \u2013", "op1": "Stigma", "op2": "Stamen", "op3": "Ovary", "op4": "Petal", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Pollen grains are collected by \u2013", "op1": "Anther", "op2": "Petal", "op3": "Stigma", "op4": "Sepal", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which part of the flower becomes the seed?", "op1": "Ovule", "op2": "Ovary", "op3": "Anther", "op4": "Stigma", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Style is a part of \u2013", "op1": "Stamen", "op2": "Pistil", "op3": "Filament", "op4": "Petal", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The stalk holding the flower is known as the \u2013", "op1": "Filament", "op2": "Stigma", "op3": "Carbuncle", "op4": "Peduncle", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following make up the corolla as a single unit?", "op1": "Petals", "op2": "Stamens", "op3": "Sepals", "op4": "Pollens", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the name given to flowering plants?", "op1": "Gymnosperms", "op2": "Bryophytes", "op3": "Pteridophytes", "op4": "Angiosperms", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Monocot flowers generally tend to have a number of petals that is divisible by \u2013", "op1": "Three", "op2": "Five", "op3": "Seven", "op4": "Two", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": ". Floral scent of a flower is produced in \u2013 Stigma Ovary Petals StamenAnswer (c).   11. Androecium is the collective name given to the group of \u2013 Pistils Stamens Sepals PetalsAnswer (b).   12. The sepals are collectively known as the \u2013 Calyx Corolla Peduncle PedicelAnswer (a).   13. Which is the male reproductive part of a flower? Stamen Pistil Stigma StyleAnswer (a).   14. Gynoecium is the collective name given to the group of \u2013 Sepals Petals Stamens PistilsAnswer (d).  ", "op1": "Stigma", "op2": "Ovary", "op3": "Petals", "op4": "Stamen", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": ". Androecium is the collective name given to the group of \u2013", "op1": "Pistils", "op2": "Stamens", "op3": "Sepals", "op4": "Petals", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": ". The sepals are collectively known as the \u2013", "op1": "Calyx", "op2": "Corolla", "op3": "Peduncle", "op4": "Pedicel", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": ". Which is the male reproductive part of a flower?", "op1": "Stamen", "op2": "Pistil", "op3": "Stigma", "op4": "Style", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": ". The Japanese art of flower arrangement is known as \u2013", "op1": "Origami", "op2": "Ikebana", "op3": "Kimono", "op4": "Bonsai", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": ". The outermost part of the flower is known as the \u2013", "op1": "Corolla", "op2": "Androecium", "op3": "Calyx", "op4": "Gynoecium", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": ". Which of the following is obtained from a flower?", "op1": "Cardamom", "op2": "Cotton", "op3": "Coffee", "op4": "Saffron", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": ". The edible part of which of the following is a flower?", "op1": "Cabbage", "op2": "Broccoli", "op3": "Lettuce", "op4": "Cilantro", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": ". Which of the following flowers is associated with heliotropism?", "op1": "Sunflower", "op2": "Marigold", "op3": "Dahlia", "op4": "Chrysanthemum", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": ". Which of the following is the single largest flower in the world?", "op1": "Amorphophallus titanium", "op2": "Rafflesia Orlandi", "op3": "Corypha Umbraculifera", "op4": "Posedonia Oceanica", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following was the first flower to blossom from the atomic-bomb scorched earth of Hiroshima?", "op1": "Hibiscus", "op2": "Rhododendron", "op3": "Bougainvillea", "op4": "Oleander", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The floral part that produces pollen grains is", "op1": "Sepal", "op2": "Petal", "op3": "Anther", "op4": "Ovary", "Answer": 2}]}